This
is
99%
invisible,
I'm
Roman
Mars.
The
five
basic
principles
of
flag
design
according
to the
North American
Vexillological
Association.
Vex
illo
logical
Vexillology
is the
study of
flags
It's the
extra
'lol'
that makes
it sound
weird
Number
one.
Keep
it simple.
The flag
should be
so simple
that a
child
can draw it
from memory.
Before I
moved to
Chicago,
in 2005,
I didn't
even
know cities
had
their own
flags.
"Most
larger
cities
have
flags."
Well I didn't
know that.
That's Ted K.,
by the way,
flag expert,
totally awesome
guy.
"I'm
the editor
of
a
scholarly
journal
on
flags
called
'Raven:
A
Journal
of Vexillology'"
And that
first city flag
I discovered in Chicago
is a beaut
A white
field,
two light
blue
horizontal
stripes,
and
four
six-pointed
red
stars
across
the middle
Number
two.
The
blue
stripes
represent
the water,
the lake, and the rivers.
Use
meaningful
symbolism.
The
red
stars
represent
significant
events
in
Chicago's
history.